<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>neat! on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</title>
    <link>/categories/neat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in neat! on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/neat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Urchins, Similar but Not</title>
      <link>/2014/02/26/two-urchins-similar-but-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/02/26/two-urchins-similar-but-not/</guid>
      <description>Great stuff from Sofia Castello y Tickell and Robert Lamb based on research from my alma mater, the Witman lab!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Kelp Barplot Ever</title>
      <link>/2014/02/02/best-kelp-barplot-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/02/02/best-kelp-barplot-ever/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re looking at growth in Laminaria (or Saccharina) kelps, and need to make a barplot&amp;hellip;why bother with the bar, really? Why not make it a kelp plot!
This from: Parke, M. 1948. Studies on British Laminariaceae. I. Growth in Laminaria saccharina (L.) Lamour. J. Mar. Biol. Ass. UK 27:709. DOI:10.1017/S0025315400056071
Pure kelpy awesomeness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saving the White Abalone</title>
      <link>/2013/07/26/saving-the-white-abalone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/07/26/saving-the-white-abalone/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m so stoked that the white abalone breeding project at BML, my phdalmamater (as it were), is rocketing forward. And I&amp;rsquo;m even more excited to see Dr. Kris Aquilino, one of my former labmates, talking about the work and communicating science LIKE A BOSS!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proxy Server Bookmarklet</title>
      <link>/2013/07/14/proxy-server-bookmarklet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/07/14/proxy-server-bookmarklet/</guid>
      <description>Like so many of us, when I&amp;rsquo;m off campus, in order to read journal pdfs and the like is a chore. I have to go to my university&amp;rsquo;s library website, login to their proxy server, go back to the article in question - either by surfing there from the library webpage, or adding the relevant text to the journal article URL.
Pain in the tuchus.
Then, the ever helpful Sean Anderson tweeted a link to a little code he&amp;rsquo;d written for a bookmarklet using Dalhousie&amp;rsquo;s ezproxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Les Miserables Larides</title>
      <link>/2013/06/18/les-miserables-larides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/06/18/les-miserables-larides/</guid>
      <description>One of the great things about field stations is the silliness they engender. I mean, there you are, in the middle of nowhere, with no one but other scientists thinking about the wonder of the natural world. Awe and wonder can only take you so far. And then, at some point, you cross over, and start to get a little silly.
It leads to things like dressing up as fouling panels, launching serious plans to make an &amp;lsquo;underwater office,&amp;rsquo; elaborate nail-polish-marking designs for crab carapaces, and no small number of pranks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuba Pteropod? The Deep by PES</title>
      <link>/2012/04/29/tuba-pteropod-the-deep-by-pes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/04/29/tuba-pteropod-the-deep-by-pes/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why, but something really caught me about this piece&amp;hellip;
by PES
What would your favorite found-object sea-creature be?
cialis generico</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Watermelon for the Aquanauts</title>
      <link>/2012/04/24/a-watermelon-for-the-aquanauts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/04/24/a-watermelon-for-the-aquanauts/</guid>
      <description>I just saw this video from the Pawlik lab doing work done in the Aquarius habitat in the Caribbean. I just adore it. There&amp;rsquo;s something about the lighthearted sense of fund and enjoyment behind the soundtrack that syncs up with the work that&amp;rsquo;s being done that captures some of the essence of what subtidal work can be (even for those of us in colder temperate climes). Enjoy this research pastiche!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awww Yeah!  Chemical Ecology Music Video Extravaganza!</title>
      <link>/2011/12/08/awww-yeah-chemical-ecology-music-video-extravaganza/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/12/08/awww-yeah-chemical-ecology-music-video-extravaganza/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m so excited. It&amp;rsquo;s one of my favorite times of year. That&amp;rsquo;s right, it&amp;rsquo;s time for the Annual Chemical Ecology Music Video Festival! Oh, J. Long, what have your students cooked up this time?
Pure awesomeness, that&amp;rsquo;s what. This year&amp;rsquo;s crop features a number of epic ballads, rap superstars, and more. I think I&amp;rsquo;ll highlight my current two favorites, but you should definitely go check out the whole bunch or go back and revisit last year&amp;rsquo;s (particularly Under the Boat (featuring K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make a Dancing Yeti Crab Video with Music </title>
      <link>/2011/12/03/how-to-make-a-dancing-yeti-crab-video-with-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/12/03/how-to-make-a-dancing-yeti-crab-video-with-music/</guid>
      <description>So, I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting some questions about how one can make their own Yeti-crabs-dance-to-music video. So here&amp;rsquo;s a quick guide for the interested folk who haven&amp;rsquo;t played around with audio or video before but want to try it out. So, here&amp;rsquo;s what I did, step-by-step, in 9 easy steps. All told, this took me, eh, 5 minutes.
(This is for iMovie, and I&amp;rsquo;ll link to a few tutorials in case you need them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dancing Yeti Crabs!  Now with a Soundtrack!</title>
      <link>/2011/12/02/dancing-yeti-crabs-now-with-soundtrack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/12/02/dancing-yeti-crabs-now-with-soundtrack/</guid>
      <description>Several years ago, when the Yeti crab, Kiwa hirsuta was first described, the world looked at a crustacean for the first time and went, &amp;ldquo;AWWWWW!!!&amp;rdquo;
I mean, how could you know love crabs from the Kiwa genus? They have fuzzy arms! And are adorable! People immediately began paying tribute with plush toys of all manner and even decorative food arrangements.
So what could be better than a plain ole&amp;rsquo; Yeti crab?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morning Kelp Forest Jam</title>
      <link>/2011/10/25/morning-kelp-forest-jam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/10/25/morning-kelp-forest-jam/</guid>
      <description>A fun undersea video with a fun soundtrack from Gary Hawkins who is generously providing me with some footage for my #SciFund video.
I may have to post more of his stuff in the future because it is AWESOME.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astrophysicists = Parasitized Killifish</title>
      <link>/2011/08/08/astrophysicists-parasitized-killifish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/08/08/astrophysicists-parasitized-killifish/</guid>
      <description>I can only assume that the authors of the every silly Saturday Morning Breakfast Cereal have taken invertebrate zoology and were fascinated by the bizarre life history cycles of trematodes and/or spent some time hanging around with Armand Kuris and Kevin Lafferty at UC Santa Barbara. Why? Because of today&amp;rsquo;s brilliant comic (see below).

Update: apparently the author&amp;rsquo;s wife is IN the Kuris lab. Ha!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Grand Experiment: Can Crowdfunding Work for Science?</title>
      <link>/2011/08/01/a-grand-experiment-can-crowdfunding-work-for-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/08/01/a-grand-experiment-can-crowdfunding-work-for-science/</guid>
      <description>There have been a steady stream of articles over the years stating that now is the time for Science to embrace Crowdfunding. It is the wave of the future, they state. It will link people to science directly. Abandon the shackles of the NSF and NIH, ye meek and mild mannered scientists. The internet is your salvation.
And along with this hoopla comes a small handfull of science crowdfunding sites, but few success stories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cufflinks for the Well Dressed Marine Scientist</title>
      <link>/2011/07/21/cufflinks-for-the-well-dressed-marine-scientist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/07/21/cufflinks-for-the-well-dressed-marine-scientist/</guid>
      <description>So, I&amp;rsquo;m-a-gettin&amp;rsquo; hitched in, what, just less that 6 weeks to a singularly lovely lady. As I determine the proper haute couture for the nuptials, I&amp;rsquo;ve begun to have fun with one piece in particular. Cuffilnks.
I mean, if you&amp;rsquo;re going to go Tux (and I do so love a good tuxedo), cufflinks are a must. But what kind of cufflinks should a gentleman marine biologist wear? Why, sea-creature themed, of course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yo!  We&#39;re Climate Scientists! </title>
      <link>/2011/05/12/yo-were-climate-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/05/12/yo-were-climate-scientists/</guid>
      <description>I realize, I have been remiss as of late posting awesome science related videos. So&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Michaelis-Menten Rules in a (simple) Lotka-Volterra World</title>
      <link>/2011/04/01/michaelis-menten-rules-in-a-simple-lotka-volterra-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/04/01/michaelis-menten-rules-in-a-simple-lotka-volterra-world/</guid>
      <description>WARNING: This blog entry contains me awkwardly groping with math. It&amp;rsquo;s not pretty. It&amp;rsquo;s not done elegantly - indeed, for problems of even moderate complexity I fired up maxima (which is totally awesome!) rather than screw up the algebra on paper. And there are a few leaps that I make that I&amp;rsquo;m sure someone could write a proof for, but, well&amp;hellip; While I fall somewhere in the middle of the theoretical - experimental axis of scientists, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean it&amp;rsquo;s something I do every day, so, expect some turbulence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ecological Nerd Musique</title>
      <link>/2011/03/17/ecological-nerd-musique/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/03/17/ecological-nerd-musique/</guid>
      <description>I woke up this morning to a wonderful email in my inbox (thanks, Fergus!) letting me know about a little musical delight. A song about diurnal zooplankton migration entitled, well, Diurnal Migration. With lyrics like Much of the ocean is not yet explored/ Though submarines pootle about the sea floor, how can you go wrong? (Also, I now have an image of Dr. M. pootling about the seafloor).
So, I went on and decided to listen to the rest of the album, Pre-Apocalyptic Love Song, by Hannah Werdmuller, an ecologist-singer-songwriter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Ecology on the Web!</title>
      <link>/2011/02/25/promoting-ecology-on-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/02/25/promoting-ecology-on-the-web/</guid>
      <description>For the past three years, the Bulletin of the Ecological Society of America has hosted a wonderful entitled &amp;ldquo;Ecology on the Web&amp;rdquo;. Under the curation of Jeff Hollister, EoW started out and grew to provide a number of links to fantastic ecological projects on the web.
If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this, you know that using the internet as a medium to facilitate communication between scientists is a passion of mine. So I was delighted when Jeff asked me to take over the feature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Residency at Deep Sea News</title>
      <link>/2011/02/18/a-brief-residency-at-deep-sea-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/02/18/a-brief-residency-at-deep-sea-news/</guid>
      <description>Hey, all! For the rest of the month, I&amp;rsquo;m the Scientist in Residence over at The Deep Sea News! Muchas gracias to Rick, Miriam, Kevin, and the rest of the crew for bringing me on board. My first post is up where I discuss some of my work on How are extinctions and invasions shaping food webs?
Also, contrary to what Rick may have you believe, I&amp;rsquo;m at NCEAS, not NESCent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diversity-Function Brought to Life</title>
      <link>/2011/01/28/diversity-function-brought-to-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/01/28/diversity-function-brought-to-life/</guid>
      <description>Last October, Colin Bates and Jeff Morales conducted a workshop on Scientific Filmmaking at my old stomping grounds, the Bodega Marine Lab. The two run an awesome organization whose sole mission is to train people in ways to tell compelling science stories via video. As someone who has worked on a scientific documentary before, film is an incredible medium to have science make a direct connection with the public. So hats off to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Your Reef On!</title>
      <link>/2011/01/18/get-your-reef-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/01/18/get-your-reef-on/</guid>
      <description>And here I thought that B-b-b-b-blue Whale would be stuck in my head all day. But now comes a second awesome marine science music video!
Two in one day! And it&amp;rsquo;s not even my birthday!
Thanks to J. Long of the recent Inducible Defense Rapinar for the pointer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I need some scat... prey base where you at?</title>
      <link>/2011/01/18/i-need-some-scat-prey-base-where-you-at/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/01/18/i-need-some-scat-prey-base-where-you-at/</guid>
      <description>I wish I could say something intelligible here, but, I love this so much and cannot stop rewatching it over and over&amp;hellip;the collision of marine bio nerdiness and pure awesome is a little overwhelming. Now if only there were tunicates involved&amp;hellip;
UBC.ZOOLOGY.GAGA.WHALE from Matt Siegle on Vimeo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kids &#43; Marine Biology = Awesome</title>
      <link>/2010/12/11/kids-marine-biology-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/12/11/kids-marine-biology-awesome/</guid>
      <description>Hey! I&amp;rsquo;m in a book! For kids! Best of all, its&amp;rsquo; a chapter to help kids get excited about marine science. I got hooked into the world of marine biology young, and have never looked back. I mean - The ocean! Sea life! It&amp;rsquo;s awesome!
So, I was delighted when Alisa Weinstein asked me a few years ago to contribute to her Earn My Keep project. The basic premise of the project is that we want our kids to learn about some of the interesting jobs and professions out there in the real world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the Grass, On the Reef - Vlogging Research</title>
      <link>/2010/06/29/in-the-grass-on-the-reef-vlogging-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/06/29/in-the-grass-on-the-reef-vlogging-research/</guid>
      <description>So, you&amp;rsquo;re an ecology power-couple starting a new life. You&amp;rsquo;ve got some elegant and incredibly ambitious experiments designed, funded, and ready to go. You&amp;rsquo;re about to revolutionize the study of coastal ecosystems&amp;hellip;but where?
Where is in the Gulf of Mexico.
And right before your work really takes flight, the Deepwater Horizon happens.
(add to that that one of you is taking some course from some silly guy on this thing called structural equation modeling - why would you ever do that?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Map of Science</title>
      <link>/2010/03/05/the-map-of-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/03/05/the-map-of-science/</guid>
      <description>Why does it take so long for awesome cutting-edge statistical to make their way over to ecology? There are a myriad of techniques out there that have been around for 20, 30, 40, or more years that could help so many ecologists from banging their head into a wall over and over and over and&amp;hellip;well, you get the point. But, it takes quite a while for them to percolate over to us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Blogging Awards!</title>
      <link>/2010/01/20/research-blogging-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/01/20/research-blogging-awards/</guid>
      <description>Well, everyone&amp;rsquo;s had a great year blogging away about the peer reviewed literature, yes? It&amp;rsquo;s time to reward those efforts! Announcing the first annual Research Blogging Awards! There are a multitude of categories, each with a $50 cash prize attached. And, here&amp;rsquo;s the kicker, the best research blog of the year will win $1,000! And with the upcoming iTablet, iPad, iSlate, iWillCallItWhatIWant tech-shininess from Apple just around the corner, it&amp;rsquo;s not a moment too soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSAs for the Sea</title>
      <link>/2009/11/06/csas-for-the-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/11/06/csas-for-the-sea/</guid>
      <description>Here at the Santa Barbara Farmer&amp;rsquo;s market, I&amp;rsquo;ve been delighted that we have local fish, ridgeback shrimp, mussels, and oysters. They&amp;rsquo;re amongst the tastiest seafood I&amp;rsquo;ve eaten (last week&amp;rsquo;s pumpkin shrimp risotto that I whipped up was one of the all time most amazing things I&amp;rsquo;ve ever cooked).
One thing I&amp;rsquo;ve always admired is that the lovely fresh seasonal sustainably farmed veggies one can get at the farmers market can also be purchased via a Community Supported Agriculture organization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who&#39;s your (academic) (great-grand) Daddy?!</title>
      <link>/2009/10/14/whos-your-academic-daddy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/10/14/whos-your-academic-daddy/</guid>
      <description>Science is a giant family. Each Professor gives &amp;ldquo;birth&amp;rdquo; to a litter of PhD students over time, many of whom go on to have their own students, who have their own students, and so on and so forth ad infinitum.
While all of us know our academic parent (right?), at least some of our sciblings (depending on the age of the lab), and usually our academic grandparent, what about our great-grandparent?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web-Based Multilevel Modeling</title>
      <link>/2009/09/18/web-based-multilevel-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/09/18/web-based-multilevel-modeling/</guid>
      <description>This is tremendously cool. A nice intuitive web-based interface for the lme4 package in R (and you neither need to know R or understand the intricacies of the lme4 package) that gives you pdf output and plots. If you just want to play around and not worry about coding things up, it&amp;rsquo;s a great little option. Be sure to check out the demo video.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New York Times Recognizes that What I Do is Hard</title>
      <link>/2009/09/09/the-new-york-times-recognizes-that-what-i-do-is-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/09/09/the-new-york-times-recognizes-that-what-i-do-is-hard/</guid>
      <description>For anyone who wants a great simple explanation for why Biodiversity-Ecosystem Function research (my field) is rather daunting, check out Olivia Judson&amp;rsquo;s New York Times blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The LTERs Get Hip!</title>
      <link>/2009/08/31/the-lters-get-hip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/08/31/the-lters-get-hip/</guid>
      <description>It seems that blogs, twitter, etc, are beginning to really leak into the consciousness of ecologists! In two weeks, I&amp;rsquo;m attending the LTER All Scientists Meeting (ASM). As I browsed through the working grounp lists, I came across the following: Blogs, Posts, and Tweets: Potential Uses of Web-Based and Social Networking Media for Communicating LTER Science and Conducting Citizen Science.
Tres cool.
The LTER network, for those unfamiliar, is perhaps the oldest network of Long Term Ecological Research projects, well, anywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m an Editor?</title>
      <link>/2009/08/06/im-an-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/08/06/im-an-editor/</guid>
      <description>So, someone over at researchblogging.org was decidedly foolish, and asked me to be one of their new editors-at-large for Biology. That means, every Thursday, I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting the three biology (typically ecology and evolution) research paper reviews linked through researchblogging.org that I enjoyed the most. My first post is up, and hopefully there will be many more to come!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tweeting A Trashy Voyage</title>
      <link>/2009/08/03/tweeting-a-trashy-voyage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/08/03/tweeting-a-trashy-voyage/</guid>
      <description>For those who aren&amp;rsquo;t following it, the SEAPLEX cruise blog is pretty amazing. SEAPLEX is a cruise being led by none other than Miriam Goldstein of The Oyster&amp;rsquo;s Garter to explore the Great North Pacific Trash Gyre.
[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_186&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;quot;300&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;quot;The Seaplex Cruise Track. Not quite a three hour tour.&amp;quot;][/caption]
OK, so, a gyre of trash may not be that great, but, you know, it&amp;rsquo;s Great. As in Awesome. By which I mean Awe-inspiring kinda Great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sir Sea Squirt</title>
      <link>/2009/06/03/sir-sea-squirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/06/03/sir-sea-squirt/</guid>
      <description>For the fashionable marine biologist: Some months back, I fell upon a website called Sir Critter selling t-shirts of organisms bedecked by a monocle, top-hats, and cane. I asked the designer if he would create a Sir Sea Squirt. He was delighted, and just posted the resulting shirt, Sir Sea Squirt.

For those of you out there who don&amp;rsquo;t think Sea Squirts are, indeed, the coolest thing on earth. ahem They also have Sir Urchin (I&amp;rsquo;m getting one with a purple S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Penis Fencing: Dangerous or Decadent?</title>
      <link>/2009/05/18/penis-fencing-deadly-or-decadent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/05/18/penis-fencing-deadly-or-decadent/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve gotta, say, Roughgarden&amp;rsquo;s The Genial Gene is so far pretty awesome. It is fulfilling its promise of being meaty, laying out the real some real testable predictions for her theory of Social Selection, and also pointing out some of the logical, historical, and cultural fallacies of sexual selection. I&amp;rsquo;m going to be very curious to read some of the reviews that will come out by sexual selection advocates, but so far, I think she is presenting a fairly compelling argument.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crocheted tunicate</title>
      <link>/2009/05/12/crocheted-tunicate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/05/12/crocheted-tunicate/</guid>
      <description>Amazing! Made by gooseflesh:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny happy loci holding hands!</title>
      <link>/2009/04/30/well-my-genes-play-well-with-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/04/30/well-my-genes-play-well-with-others/</guid>
      <description>A few years back, I read Evolution&amp;rsquo;s Rainbow by Joan Roughgarden, and was a huge fan. In it, she builds a compelling argument that sex and gender are two different independently assorting quantitative genetic trains. I.e., Your sex (anatomy) and gender (behavior and sexuality)? Not actually the same thing. Also, not binary. Both (yes, sex, too) are continuous traits.
She builds a strong case for this both based on the wild variety of mating strategies out in nature (and shows how they don&amp;rsquo;t really fit into the binary gender paradigm of sexual selection) and even more thoroughly through human biology and history.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>