<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>science online on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</title>
    <link>/categories/science-online/</link>
    <description>Recent content in science online on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/science-online/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Urchins, Similar but Not</title>
      <link>/2014/02/26/two-urchins-similar-but-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/02/26/two-urchins-similar-but-not/</guid>
      <description>Great stuff from Sofia Castello y Tickell and Robert Lamb based on research from my alma mater, the Witman lab!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Use Different Social Media Platforms for Science</title>
      <link>/2013/07/12/which-social-media-platform-should-i-use-for-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/07/12/which-social-media-platform-should-i-use-for-science/</guid>
      <description>OK, so, you&amp;rsquo;re a scientist interested in jumping into the world of online social networking for interacting with colleagues, fun and profitbringing science to the world at large. Fantastic!
So, you log on, and are suddenly confronted by a dizzying array of sites you could use to communicate. Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, Google+, Myspace (yes, it&amp;rsquo;s back), Blogspot, Wordpress, FriendFeed, Tumblr, &amp;hellip;. I could go on for a while. And then you may also have concerns about mixing personal and private.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#Scio13 and Beyond</title>
      <link>/2013/02/04/scio13-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/02/04/scio13-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>While I&amp;rsquo;ve been active in using online spaces for scientific activities - blogging, tweeting, crowdfunding, and much much more - for a looong time. I&amp;rsquo;ve found it&amp;rsquo;s benefitted me greatly as a scientist. I&amp;rsquo;ve also formed a deep love for the community I&amp;rsquo;ve found in the online science world (to name just a few).
And yet, until this year, I&amp;rsquo;d never been to science online before.
This year, I finally remedied that.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>