<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>paper review on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</title>
    <link>/categories/paper-review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in paper review on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/paper-review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Positive Multifunctionality ≠ All Functions Are Positive</title>
      <link>/2014/09/25/positive-multifunctionality-all-functions-are-positive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/09/25/positive-multifunctionality-all-functions-are-positive/</guid>
      <description>Positive Multifunctionality ≠ All Functions Are Positive
I was dismayed this morning to read Bradford et al.&amp;lsquo;s recently accepted paper Discontinuity in the responses of ecosystem processes and multifunctionality to altered soil community composition in PNAS for several reasons.
The paper itself is really cool. They manipulated community complexity and nutrient conditions in the Ecotron, and then looked at five soil ecosystem functions. They then looked at whether complexity influenced multi functionality (as well as N), and found, indeed, it did!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring is sproinging earlier than we thought</title>
      <link>/2012/05/08/spring-is-sproinging-earlier-than-we-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/05/08/spring-is-sproinging-earlier-than-we-thought/</guid>
      <description>Climate change is speeding up the timing of plants growing &amp;amp; flowering. It&amp;rsquo;s an old trope we&amp;rsquo;re all used to hearing by now. Spring warms up earlier, and plants shift their timing - their phenology. This shift in phenology is going to have big consequences for things like agricultural production, the ability for wildlife to find food, the ski season, etc. Important, right? Something we might want to predict. So, we&amp;rsquo;ve been running experiments for years, looking at climate change scenarios, and finding out how much earlier plants will do their thing, and we&amp;rsquo;ve gotten some pretty good results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diversity Loss v. Environmental Change: The Story of the Paper</title>
      <link>/2012/05/02/diversity-loss-v-environmental-change-the-story-of-the-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/05/02/diversity-loss-v-environmental-change-the-story-of-the-paper/</guid>
      <description>Just over a year and a half ago, I was lucky enough to be in a room with some of the world&amp;rsquo;s top authorities on the consequences of species loss at the National Center for Ecological Analysis and Synthesis. We were worried. When Brad Cardinale asked, &amp;ldquo;So, where does diversity loss rank? As important as climate change? Rampant nutrient runoff from agriculture? I mean, come on, how important is it, really?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dancing Yeti Crabs!  Now with a Soundtrack!</title>
      <link>/2011/12/02/dancing-yeti-crabs-now-with-soundtrack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/12/02/dancing-yeti-crabs-now-with-soundtrack/</guid>
      <description>Several years ago, when the Yeti crab, Kiwa hirsuta was first described, the world looked at a crustacean for the first time and went, &amp;ldquo;AWWWWW!!!&amp;rdquo;
I mean, how could you know love crabs from the Kiwa genus? They have fuzzy arms! And are adorable! People immediately began paying tribute with plush toys of all manner and even decorative food arrangements.
So what could be better than a plain ole&amp;rsquo; Yeti crab?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can We Reduce the Carbon Cost of Scientific Mega-Meetings?</title>
      <link>/2011/11/22/can-we-reduce-the-carbon-cost-of-scientific-mega-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/11/22/can-we-reduce-the-carbon-cost-of-scientific-mega-meetings/</guid>
      <description>I admit it. I love big scientific meetings. There&amp;rsquo;s something about the intense intellectual hubbub of thousands of my fields greatest minds gathered in one place for a few days of showing off the latest, greatest, flashiest work that just fills me with joy. Also a need to sleep for a week afterwards due to my brain going at a Matrix-like pace to keep up with all of the new and interesting information while spouting off ideas, critiques, beginning collaborations, and constantly questing to understand the growing shape of the research fields that interest me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story Behind the Paper: Climate Change and Kelp Forest Food Webs</title>
      <link>/2011/07/11/the-story-of-a-paper-climate-change-and-kelp-forest-food-webs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/07/11/the-story-of-a-paper-climate-change-and-kelp-forest-food-webs/</guid>
      <description>Yay! First paper of my postdoc is out in the August 2011 issue of Global Change Biology!
Woohoo!
So, what have I been doing for the past few years of my life?
In brief summary: Kelp. Food webs. Climate change. A potent combination.
And if you want the punchline without digging into the rest of this article, it is this: the diverse, complex food webs of southern California kelp forest will likely be greatly simplified if climate change leads to big storms every year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should We Eat Fish?  The Online Discussion</title>
      <link>/2011/05/18/should-we-eat-fish-the-online-discussion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/05/18/should-we-eat-fish-the-online-discussion/</guid>
      <description>One of the main reasons science blogs excite me is the possibility of communication between scientists. It allows for a medium that scientists can use to hash out ideas and do so publicly. This has the added advantage that those who are not big names in a field or somesuch can listen in, as it were, or even step in and participate.
The discussion of science between scientists here, online, also has the added advantage of allowing the public to see inside of scientific debates and discussions in realtime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diversity: It Matters! (for plants &amp; algae)</title>
      <link>/2011/03/29/diversity-it-matters-for-plants/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/03/29/diversity-it-matters-for-plants/</guid>
      <description>Geological time has witnessed 5 extinction crises. Now we&amp;rsquo;re in the middle of the 6th - this time driven by man. What&amp;rsquo;s unprecedented, however, is the rate we are driving species extinct. For many taxa, it&amp;rsquo;s faster than we&amp;rsquo;ve seen in geological time (see here for discussion).
So? Will vast reductions in the diversity of species on earth matter? I mean, heck, maybe we only need two or three of each taxa, and we&amp;rsquo;re all good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fingerprint of Fishing</title>
      <link>/2010/11/17/the-fingerprint-of-fishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/11/17/the-fingerprint-of-fishing/</guid>
      <description>How is fishing changing the ocean? This simple question has motivated a slew of fantastic research. One of the most pervasive ideas has been that of Fishing Down Marine Food Webs. Popularized by Daniel Pauly and colleagues in their 1998 paper, the idea simply states that when humans began fishing, we hit the top predators first. Gradually, as we depleted those stocks, human fishing moved down to the next trophic level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Truth in a Messy World</title>
      <link>/2010/09/13/finding-truth-in-a-messy-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/09/13/finding-truth-in-a-messy-world/</guid>
      <description>*-note, this was derived from a combination of emails between myself and my former phd advisor. See if you can pick out who is arguing what and where. It&amp;rsquo;s fun - well, for some of you, anyway.
How do we know the world?
This is a seemingly simple and vast question - one with no answer. And yet, it is at the core of every single scientific endeavor. We make choices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privatizing the Reviewer Commons</title>
      <link>/2010/07/20/privatizing-the-reviewer-commons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/07/20/privatizing-the-reviewer-commons/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s face it. The current journal system is slowly breaking down - in Ecology if not in other disciplines as well. The number of submissions is going up exponentially. At the same time, journals are finding it harder and harder to find reviewers. Statistics such as editors contacting 10 reviewers to find 3 are not uncommon. People don&amp;rsquo;t respond, they take a long time to review, or just take a long time and THEN don&amp;rsquo;t respond leading to a need for still more reviewers to be found (this has held up 2 of my pubs for 3+ extra months).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Not Log-Transform Count Data, Bitches!</title>
      <link>/2010/06/17/do-not-log-transform-count-data-bitches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/06/17/do-not-log-transform-count-data-bitches/</guid>
      <description>OK, so, the title of this article is actually Do not log-transform count data, but, as @ascidacea mentioned, you just can&amp;rsquo;t resist adding the &amp;ldquo;bitches&amp;rdquo; to the end.
Onwards.
If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, when you learned experimental stats, you were taught to worship at the throne of the Normal Distribution. Always check your data and make sure it is normally distributed! Or, make sure that whatever lines you fit to it have normally distributed error around them!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Dissertation in Under 7 Minutes</title>
      <link>/2010/04/01/my-dissertation-in-under-7-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/04/01/my-dissertation-in-under-7-minutes/</guid>
      <description>I recently attended the DISCCRS symposium for recent PhDs of a wide variety of disciplines whose work (past or present) deals with climate change. The week-long meeting was phenomenal, seeding me with thoughts, ideas, and basically making me feel quite good about the work I&amp;rsquo;m doing (if also very pessimistic about how society is dealing with Climate Change). Perhaps one of the most interesting exercises of the whole thing was something we had to do as a sort of getting-to-know-you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Future: Hot n&#39; Tasty?</title>
      <link>/2010/03/31/our-future-hot-n-tasty/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/03/31/our-future-hot-n-tasty/</guid>
      <description>Climate change. It&amp;rsquo;s going to wreak no small amount of havoc on mother nature (and if you&amp;rsquo;re reading this but think all of this climate change stuff is poppycock, please visit Skeptical Science and then come back). How good of a guide is our intuition for what will happen?
This is a great question when it comes to predator-prey relationships and the food chain. One may well think that, heck, from first principles we know that adding heat to a system speeds things up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Conservation Horizon</title>
      <link>/2010/01/21/the-conservation-horizon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/01/21/the-conservation-horizon/</guid>
      <description>Every so often, a conservation problem rears its head that, upon reflection, we realize we had some inkling of even decades ago. Global warming, biofuels, overfishing, etc. The information was there, but scarce, buried in obscurity, or seemingly counterintuitive. Why not try and recognize the crucial questions early, before the lobster is out of the trap, so to speak? (What, I&amp;rsquo;m a marine biologist!)
Businesses has recognized the need to spot emerging trends with scant information and regularly engages in an exercise called Horizon Scanning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sea Stars on Acid</title>
      <link>/2009/09/10/sea-stars-on-acid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/09/10/sea-stars-on-acid/</guid>
      <description>As an ecologist working in temperate climes, I&amp;rsquo;ve been following the ocean acidification field with some interest. It&amp;rsquo;s always been obvious to me how acidification has enormous ramifications for coral reefs and other tropical marine ecosystems. They exist in warm waters already, often close to their thermal maxima. Acidifying the water around them at any creatures using calcium carbonate seems like a recipe for disaster.
[caption id=&amp;quot;attachment_209&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;quot;alignright&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;quot;300&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;quot;How not to do acidification research on Pacific salmon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m an Editor?</title>
      <link>/2009/08/06/im-an-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/08/06/im-an-editor/</guid>
      <description>So, someone over at researchblogging.org was decidedly foolish, and asked me to be one of their new editors-at-large for Biology. That means, every Thursday, I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting the three biology (typically ecology and evolution) research paper reviews linked through researchblogging.org that I enjoyed the most. My first post is up, and hopefully there will be many more to come!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Ideas in Ecology and Reviewing</title>
      <link>/2009/05/10/new-ideas-in-ecology-and-reviewing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/05/10/new-ideas-in-ecology-and-reviewing/</guid>
      <description>Recently on ecolog-l, there has been a thread going around about journal publishing - open access v. pay-for access, impact factor, elitism, reviewing, etc. The central question seems to be, is the publication system somehow broken? Do we need to fix it? Is the model of journals such as PLoS Biology or The Open Ecology Journal not enough?
I think the answer is that in the realm of experimental or solid theoretical work, yes, the open access model of science publishing is alive and well (although I often wished that more of the journals out there, such as Research Letters in Ecology, got more attention - but the question of why to submit in a new journal, and what makes a journal high on ones priority list is a whole different ball of wax).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>snails going nom nom nom = productive diverse tidepools?</title>
      <link>/2009/04/24/snails-going-nom-nom-nom-productive-diverse-tidepools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/04/24/snails-going-nom-nom-nom-productive-diverse-tidepools/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;gold standard&amp;rdquo; experimental design for asking how do changes in biodiversity change ecosystem function has been to randomly assemble communities of varying species richness, but equal abundance, and examining differences in function from one level of richness to the next.
But let&amp;rsquo;s be honest. Changes in diversity due to impacts by man will not be random. In many ways, the early (and much maligned) designs of Tilman and colleagues are really more relevant to realistic biodiversity change scenarios than random assembly experiments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>when NOT to MANOVA</title>
      <link>/2009/03/09/when-not-to-manova/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/03/09/when-not-to-manova/</guid>
      <description>And now its time for a multivariate stats geek out.
The statistics that we use determine the inferences we draw from our data. The more statistical tools you learn to use, the more likely you are likely to slip on a loose bit of data, and stab yourself in the eyeball with your swiss-army-knife of p values. It&amp;rsquo;s happened to all of us, and it is rarely due to willful misconduct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rum, Sea Squirts, and the Lash!</title>
      <link>/2009/02/03/rum-sea-squirts-and-the-lash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/02/03/rum-sea-squirts-and-the-lash/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;But assuming that the would-be scientist managed to avoid, or survive, the potentially dire consequences of scurvy, dysentery and malaria, that his ship was not sunk in bad weather or driven onto an uncharted rock or reef, and that his journals and specimens were not destroyed by shipboard fungus, insects, rodents or cow or sheep urine, he still had several major problems to overcome in order to undertake remotely adequate deep sea research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>invasive sea-squirt-a-palooza</title>
      <link>/2009/01/31/invasive-sea-squirt-a-palooza/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/01/31/invasive-sea-squirt-a-palooza/</guid>
      <description>Attention tunicate nerds! The Proceedings of the 2nd International Invasive Sea Squirt Symposium (I love that name) (and, OK, it&amp;rsquo;s Conference, not Symposium, but how could I resist renaming it to something more fun!) are now online! And there&amp;rsquo;s a lot there to check out.
First off, we now know the tunicate formerly known as Didemnum sp. A, D. vestum, D. vexillum, D. lutarium, D. lahillei, D. helgolandicum, and the ever popular D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the light!  the heat!  the feedback!</title>
      <link>/2009/01/28/the-light-the-heat-the-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/01/28/the-light-the-heat-the-feedback/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, the devil IS in the details. I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about feedbacks between community community structure and function lately, and run into a few curious roadblocks, as well as one very very interesting story.
First, the roadblocks. Just what do we mean by structure and function, particularly in reference to a biological community? Structure seems obvious - the static properties of a biological system that we can go out, stare at, and say,&amp;ldquo;Oh, yes, hello structure!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>