<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rb editor selection on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</title>
    <link>/tags/rb-editor-selection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rb editor selection on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/rb-editor-selection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Privatizing the Reviewer Commons</title>
      <link>/2010/07/20/privatizing-the-reviewer-commons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/07/20/privatizing-the-reviewer-commons/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s face it. The current journal system is slowly breaking down - in Ecology if not in other disciplines as well. The number of submissions is going up exponentially. At the same time, journals are finding it harder and harder to find reviewers. Statistics such as editors contacting 10 reviewers to find 3 are not uncommon. People don&amp;rsquo;t respond, they take a long time to review, or just take a long time and THEN don&amp;rsquo;t respond leading to a need for still more reviewers to be found (this has held up 2 of my pubs for 3+ extra months).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viva la Neo-Fisherian Liberation Front!</title>
      <link>/2010/02/15/viva-la-neo-fisherian-liberation-front/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/02/15/viva-la-neo-fisherian-liberation-front/</guid>
      <description>p≤0.05
 Significant p-values. For so many scientists using statistics, this is your lord. Your master. Heck, it has its own facebook group filed under religious affiliations (ok, so, maybe I created that.) And it is a concept to whose slavish devotion we may have sacrificed a good bit of forward progress in science over the past half century. Time to blow up the cathedral! Or so says Stuart Hurlbert and Celia Lombardi in a recent fascinating review.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>