<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>#SciFund on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</title>
    <link>/categories/#scifund/</link>
    <description>Recent content in #SciFund on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/#scifund/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I want to know what *YOU* think about review, preprints, and publication</title>
      <link>/2013/02/25/i-want-to-know-what-you-think-about-review-preprints-and-publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/02/25/i-want-to-know-what-you-think-about-review-preprints-and-publication/</guid>
      <description>As part of the OpenPub project, we&amp;rsquo;re soliciting folk to send us videos about their experience with the scholarly publication process. We want to use these to try and crowdfund the development of OpenPub - our preprint server with robust tools for discussion and interaction. Interested? Check out the full request over here and/or email me!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AAAS Webinar on Science Crowdfunding</title>
      <link>/2013/02/06/aaas-webinar-on-science-crowdfunding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/02/06/aaas-webinar-on-science-crowdfunding/</guid>
      <description>(x-posted from the #SciFund Blog)
Last week, Ethan Perlstein, Erica Hermsen, and I were part of a webinar from AAAS Member Central. It was an interesting peak into what the three of us thought of this new opportunity as well as a venue for a discussion for some important issues. Check it out below!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#Scio13 and Beyond</title>
      <link>/2013/02/04/scio13-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/02/04/scio13-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>While I&amp;rsquo;ve been active in using online spaces for scientific activities - blogging, tweeting, crowdfunding, and much much more - for a looong time. I&amp;rsquo;ve found it&amp;rsquo;s benefitted me greatly as a scientist. I&amp;rsquo;ve also formed a deep love for the community I&amp;rsquo;ve found in the online science world (to name just a few).
And yet, until this year, I&amp;rsquo;d never been to science online before.
This year, I finally remedied that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crowdfunding in the Peer Reviewed Literature</title>
      <link>/2013/01/28/crowdfunding-in-the-peer-reviewed-literature/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/01/28/crowdfunding-in-the-peer-reviewed-literature/</guid>
      <description>(x-posted at the #SciFund Blog)
The final version of Wheat et al.&amp;lsquo;s paper Raising money for scientific research through crowdfunding is out in Trends in Ecology and Evolution. A more hefty piece of #SciFund analysis is behind it (slowed down in no small part because of my sloooow processing of new data in fancy models). The Wheat et al. paper is a lovely short piece that Rachel and Yiwei (who crowdfunded the excellent Alaska Predator Research Expedition that has it&amp;rsquo;s new website over here) were gracious enough to ask Jai and I to participate in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#SciFund Round 1 - Results &amp; Ravings</title>
      <link>/2012/07/09/scifund-round-1-results-ravings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/07/09/scifund-round-1-results-ravings/</guid>
      <description>So, you want to hear my vision for what #SciFund tells us about the future of science funding &amp;amp; engagement, and back it up with data? Bam! Here you go.
This is my talk about the results from Round 1 of #SciFund from an NCEAS Ecolunch. The slides are below the video. Enjoy!
Slides from #SciFund talk at NCEAS Ecolunch
View more presentations from Jarrett Byrnes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#SciFund Round 2 FTW!</title>
      <link>/2012/06/04/scifund-round-2-ftw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/06/04/scifund-round-2-ftw/</guid>
      <description>SciFund Round 2 is now complete, and it pulled in $100,345 for science! 43% of the projects achieved 100% or more of their goal - almost double of round 1 - and 60% of all funds asked for were secured. Numerous projects that didn&amp;rsquo;t fully reach their goal were above 80%. A TON of great research is going to come out of this, and I am excited!
Science crowdfunding continues to grow as a viable source of research fund.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beware of the teeny tiny crabs.  They will cut you!</title>
      <link>/2012/05/11/beware-of-the-teeny-tiny-crabs-they-will-cut-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/05/11/beware-of-the-teeny-tiny-crabs-they-will-cut-you/</guid>
      <description>Happy Friday, everyone. To celebrate the end of the week, I leave you with what is hands down my favorite #SciFund video from round 2. And I don&amp;rsquo;t just say this because it was made by a collaborator of mine of the #SciFund paper that we happen to be editing right this very moment (or, in half an hour or so). I say this because it is a beautiful example of the fusion of (silly) Art and Science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#SciFund 2 has launched!</title>
      <link>/2012/05/01/scifund-2-has-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/05/01/scifund-2-has-launched/</guid>
      <description>Woohoo! #SciFund 2 is off to the races! I am in awe of the nearly 70 scientists who have put their work up for your enjoyment. I&amp;rsquo;ll be featuring a few marine projects in the next few days, but, for now, get on over there, check it out, and help us crowdfund some amazing science!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to prepare for #SciFund - by crowdfunding science!</title>
      <link>/2012/03/31/how-to-prepare-for-scifund-by-crowdfunding-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/03/31/how-to-prepare-for-scifund-by-crowdfunding-science/</guid>
      <description>Are you excited about seeing the 125 hot science projects that got submitted to #SciFund2? Can&amp;rsquo;t wait the additional month for those projects to post themselves online? Want to fund some awesome science right now? Maybe you signed up and want to earn some pre-#SciFund karma?
Well fear not! The Science tag on Rockethub has been taking off! A few folk were so excited about crowdfunding their work that they couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait for #SciFund 2!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Missing my Statsy Goodness? Check out #SciFund!</title>
      <link>/2012/03/06/missing-my-statsy-goodness-check-out-scifund/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/03/06/missing-my-statsy-goodness-check-out-scifund/</guid>
      <description>I know, I know, I have been kinda lame about posting here lately. But that&amp;rsquo;s because my posting muscle has been focused on the new analyses for what makes a succesful #SciFund proposal. I&amp;rsquo;ve been posting them at the #SciFund blog under the Analysis tag - so check it out. There&amp;rsquo;s some fun stats, and you get to watch me be a social scientist for a minute. Viva la interdisciplinarity! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#SciFund 2 Launches!</title>
      <link>/2012/03/03/scifund-2-launches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/03/03/scifund-2-launches/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s right, folk, last time we had 49 scientists bring in ~1400 people to check out their hot science and fund it to the tune of $76,000. And that was when we had no idea what we were doing. And now it&amp;rsquo;s time for round 2! We&amp;rsquo;re going to have a little more community review, some training, and we have a whole boatload of lessons learned.
So if you&amp;rsquo;re a scientist who wants to crowdfund their research, go and sign up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#SciFund is OVER!  </title>
      <link>/2011/12/16/scifund-is-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/12/16/scifund-is-over/</guid>
      <description>After 45 days, with $76,230 raised from 1440 people, I am a pretty proud papa.
My own project hit 70% bringing in $4,600 for kelp forest research. While not complete, it funds one full round of sampling trips and a little extra, so, I&amp;rsquo;m super excited! And now the data from RocketHub and #SciFund participants begins to flow in. Time to start doing some analyses on what worked, what didn&amp;rsquo;t, and begin to lay out the future of crowdfunding in science!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Won&#39;t You #SciFund?</title>
      <link>/2011/12/13/wont-you-scifund/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/12/13/wont-you-scifund/</guid>
      <description>With 4 days left, Tim Bonebreak asks, won&amp;rsquo;t you #SciFund? We&amp;rsquo;ve got 6 projects fully funded, and a number that are on the verge! I am at 65% myself! So achingly close!
So come on over and #SciFund scientific research and help affect a revolution in how scientists interact with the world around them!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#SciFund Preview....</title>
      <link>/2011/10/24/scifund-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/10/24/scifund-preview/</guid>
      <description>Whew, it&amp;rsquo;s been a bit since I posted here. Rest assured, little sea squirts, there are some interesting new things in the works. Some things that are science-y (in which I try and use this blog as a sounding board/ lab notebook) and some things not so much.
In the not so much category, a ton of my time has lately been going to the organizing of the #SciFund challenge - a large initiative to try and crowdfunding for science!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>