<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>publishing on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</title>
    <link>/categories/publishing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in publishing on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/publishing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An Open Letter to ISI Web of Knowledge, Google Scholar, and SciVerse Scopus </title>
      <link>/2013/09/05/an-open-letter-to-isi-web-of-knowledge-google-scholar-and-sciverse-scopus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/09/05/an-open-letter-to-isi-web-of-knowledge-google-scholar-and-sciverse-scopus/</guid>
      <description>_A bit of context first. This letter arose as a result of discussions regarding citations practices in meta-analyses on Twitter several weeks ago. We all agreed citations of work within meta-analyses should be counted, but noted that many modern citation counting services disregard any citations not in the main body of a paper. Appendix citations are dropped, however. And due to a variety of restrictions, we often only cite the papers we use as data in appendices, and so are not counted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PeerJ Turns One!</title>
      <link>/2013/06/13/peerj-turns-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/06/13/peerj-turns-one/</guid>
      <description>x-posted from openpub
One year ago, one of the more intereting experiments in open access publishing - PeerJ - launched. It&amp;rsquo;s model of membership rather than paying by the article is still something people are grappling with - it&amp;rsquo;s just so different, so delightfully disruptive. Not only that, but PeerJ has stepped in to fill the void in providing a biology preprint server (which we have used), as well as coming up with a more intuitive interface for commentary on preprints and published work - along with supplying reviews alongside published work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Peer Review Experience Ever</title>
      <link>/2013/05/10/best-peer-review-experience-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/05/10/best-peer-review-experience-ever/</guid>
      <description>So, I recently submitted a piece regarding the future of scholarly publishing in Ecology &amp;amp; Evolutionary Biology. Simultaneous to posting, I put up a preprint in PeerJ Preprints and also put it on Google Docs for line by line commentary (which you are welcome to give!). I asked in both places that commenters identify themselves, unless they felt deeply uncomfortable.
OMG the experience has been amazing!
At PeerJ you can comment on the main page of the article, and others can rate it - which is fantastic - and I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten some wonderful feedback there (thanks Lars!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Preprint Experiment: Four Pillars and a Foundation for the Future of Scholarly Publishing</title>
      <link>/2013/05/07/a-preprint-experiment-four-pillars-and-a-foundation-for-the-future-of-scholarly-publishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/05/07/a-preprint-experiment-four-pillars-and-a-foundation-for-the-future-of-scholarly-publishing/</guid>
      <description>x-post from the OpenPub Project blog
So, we got together, had two working group meetings to discuss the future of scholarly publishing in Ecology, Evolutionary Biology, and the Earth and Ocean Sciences. What were were thinking that entire time?
We&amp;rsquo;ve just submitted a piece that brings together our broad ideas (some of which have been seen before), but, simultaneous to publication, we&amp;rsquo;ve also decided to put up a preprint. Why? Simply put, immediate access is one of our four pillars of the future of scholarly publication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I want to know what *YOU* think about review, preprints, and publication</title>
      <link>/2013/02/25/i-want-to-know-what-you-think-about-review-preprints-and-publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/02/25/i-want-to-know-what-you-think-about-review-preprints-and-publication/</guid>
      <description>As part of the OpenPub project, we&amp;rsquo;re soliciting folk to send us videos about their experience with the scholarly publication process. We want to use these to try and crowdfund the development of OpenPub - our preprint server with robust tools for discussion and interaction. Interested? Check out the full request over here and/or email me!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-Publication Commentary - a Google Hangout Discussion</title>
      <link>/2012/07/06/post-publication-commentary-a-google-hangout-discussion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/07/06/post-publication-commentary-a-google-hangout-discussion/</guid>
      <description>After the fantastic NCEAS working group on the future of scholarly publishing in EEB (big success - stay tuned for more news on that front!), I participated in a really interesting online discussion about Post-Publication peer review with Carl Boettiger, Jamie Ashlander, and Scott Chamberlain. The conversation was great, and I think brought up a lot of interesting points - both that echoed some discussions in our group and went far beyond them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Haus Conclusion: Peer Review or Bust!</title>
      <link>/2012/02/13/open-haus-conclusions-peer-review-or-bust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/02/13/open-haus-conclusions-peer-review-or-bust/</guid>
      <description>Friday&amp;rsquo;s NCEAS discussion about changing the future of scientific publishing was fascinating. We had a wide variety of views about the current system, what it&amp;rsquo;s adding to our papers, if the problems really are problems, and why we got here. But there was one thing that came up again and again, that even the most skeptical status quo folk in the crowd agreed was where the true value of the current journal system lies -</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Haus: The Future of Scholarly Publishing</title>
      <link>/2012/02/10/open-haus-the-future-of-scholarly-publishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/02/10/open-haus-the-future-of-scholarly-publishing/</guid>
      <description>Today at The National Center for Ecological Analysis and Synthesis we&amp;rsquo;re having an open discussion about the future of scholarly publishing. I may post some notes from it later, but, Stephanie Pau and I have compiled a list of thought questions and helpful links to help folk prep. And, as it was an interesting gathering of linkage, I thought it mide be useful more broadly. So, below is the text of my email and the useful links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Vision for the Future of Scholarly Publishing</title>
      <link>/2012/01/31/a-vision-for-the-future-of-scholarly-publishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/01/31/a-vision-for-the-future-of-scholarly-publishing/</guid>
      <description>In many ways, the Research Works Act has been a blessing (see excellent link round up here). It has taken the moderately complacent but always grousing scientific community and whipped our feelings about the current state and cost of scientific publishing into a white hot fury. Ideas are bandied about, critiques given, and people begin to take action.
So what is the way forward? Certainly we are not getting away from journals in the near term.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story Behind the Paper: Climate Change and Kelp Forest Food Webs</title>
      <link>/2011/07/11/the-story-of-a-paper-climate-change-and-kelp-forest-food-webs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/07/11/the-story-of-a-paper-climate-change-and-kelp-forest-food-webs/</guid>
      <description>Yay! First paper of my postdoc is out in the August 2011 issue of Global Change Biology!
Woohoo!
So, what have I been doing for the past few years of my life?
In brief summary: Kelp. Food webs. Climate change. A potent combination.
And if you want the punchline without digging into the rest of this article, it is this: the diverse, complex food webs of southern California kelp forest will likely be greatly simplified if climate change leads to big storms every year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Ecology on the Web!</title>
      <link>/2011/02/25/promoting-ecology-on-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/02/25/promoting-ecology-on-the-web/</guid>
      <description>For the past three years, the Bulletin of the Ecological Society of America has hosted a wonderful entitled &amp;ldquo;Ecology on the Web&amp;rdquo;. Under the curation of Jeff Hollister, EoW started out and grew to provide a number of links to fantastic ecological projects on the web.
If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this, you know that using the internet as a medium to facilitate communication between scientists is a passion of mine. So I was delighted when Jeff asked me to take over the feature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privatizing the Reviewer Commons</title>
      <link>/2010/07/20/privatizing-the-reviewer-commons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/07/20/privatizing-the-reviewer-commons/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s face it. The current journal system is slowly breaking down - in Ecology if not in other disciplines as well. The number of submissions is going up exponentially. At the same time, journals are finding it harder and harder to find reviewers. Statistics such as editors contacting 10 reviewers to find 3 are not uncommon. People don&amp;rsquo;t respond, they take a long time to review, or just take a long time and THEN don&amp;rsquo;t respond leading to a need for still more reviewers to be found (this has held up 2 of my pubs for 3+ extra months).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Ideas in Ecology and Reviewing</title>
      <link>/2009/05/10/new-ideas-in-ecology-and-reviewing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/05/10/new-ideas-in-ecology-and-reviewing/</guid>
      <description>Recently on ecolog-l, there has been a thread going around about journal publishing - open access v. pay-for access, impact factor, elitism, reviewing, etc. The central question seems to be, is the publication system somehow broken? Do we need to fix it? Is the model of journals such as PLoS Biology or The Open Ecology Journal not enough?
I think the answer is that in the realm of experimental or solid theoretical work, yes, the open access model of science publishing is alive and well (although I often wished that more of the journals out there, such as Research Letters in Ecology, got more attention - but the question of why to submit in a new journal, and what makes a journal high on ones priority list is a whole different ball of wax).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>