<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>howto on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</title>
    <link>/categories/howto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in howto on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/howto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching for Opportunities in Ecology &amp; Environmental Science for Recent Grads</title>
      <link>/2013/12/19/searching-for-opportunities-in-ecology-environmental-science-for-recent-grads/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/12/19/searching-for-opportunities-in-ecology-environmental-science-for-recent-grads/</guid>
      <description>So, you&amp;rsquo;re graduating with a biology or environmental science or marine bio degree! Hurray! You&amp;rsquo;ve finished your stint at college, and you&amp;rsquo;ve gained a lot of new skills. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve done some time in research, maybe not (!!!), but now that you&amp;rsquo;ve wrapped up, you want to find a job in the environmental sciences. Something that will give you research experience, and help you on your way to either a career or deciding whether you want to go into research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running R2WinBUGS on a Mac Running OSX</title>
      <link>/2012/01/18/running-r2winbugs-on-a-mac-running-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/01/18/running-r2winbugs-on-a-mac-running-osx/</guid>
      <description>I have long used JAGS to do all of my Bayesian work on my mac. Early on, I tried to figure out how to install WinBUGS and OpenBUGS and their accompanying R libraries on my mac, but, to no avail. I just had too hard of a time getting them running and gave up.
But, it would seem that some things have changed with Wine lately, and it is now possible to not only get WinBUGS itself running nicely on a mac, but to also get R2WinBUGS to run as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make a Dancing Yeti Crab Video with Music </title>
      <link>/2011/12/03/how-to-make-a-dancing-yeti-crab-video-with-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/12/03/how-to-make-a-dancing-yeti-crab-video-with-music/</guid>
      <description>So, I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting some questions about how one can make their own Yeti-crabs-dance-to-music video. So here&amp;rsquo;s a quick guide for the interested folk who haven&amp;rsquo;t played around with audio or video before but want to try it out. So, here&amp;rsquo;s what I did, step-by-step, in 9 easy steps. All told, this took me, eh, 5 minutes.
(This is for iMovie, and I&amp;rsquo;ll link to a few tutorials in case you need them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>