<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>meetings on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</title>
    <link>/categories/meetings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in meetings on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/meetings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking the Ecological Conversation Online</title>
      <link>/2012/08/15/taking-the-ecological-conversation-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/08/15/taking-the-ecological-conversation-online/</guid>
      <description>At ESA this year, I gave a talk in a symposium about changing the culture of ecology. The talk was entitled Taking the Ecological Conversation Online and summarized what I thought were the benefits of engaging in online activities. As this was a scientific audience interested in how we might change the culture of Ecology to improve our science, I focused the talk not on what I feel are the outreach &amp;amp; public engagement benefits of going online - those are both obvious and legion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Friday at #ESA2012</title>
      <link>/2012/08/10/final-friday-at-esa2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/08/10/final-friday-at-esa2012/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of catching on Friday. Last day, and still lots of fantastic talks! What a wonderful meeting that this has been. (Eating at The Farm didn&amp;rsquo;t hurt either&amp;hellip;)
8:00 COS 176-1 Cavanaugh, KC1, SL Davis1, JS Gosnell2, J Ahumada3 and S Andelman3, (1)University of California Santa Barbara, (2)University of California, Santa Barbara, (3)Conservation International. Interactions among climate, biodiversity, and ecosystem services in tropical forest ecosystems. C123
8am SYMP 23-1Costanza, R, Portland State University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday #ESA2012 Schedule</title>
      <link>/2012/08/09/thursday-esa2012-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/08/09/thursday-esa2012-schedule/</guid>
      <description>ALl right - here&amp;rsquo;s my Thursday schedule (mostly for myself so I can keep track of it on my phone). I think in the morning, I just might park myself in the session on climate change &amp;amp; communities as one of my main interests for this meeting is&amp;hellip;climate change and communities. Also, I&amp;rsquo;m guessing I&amp;rsquo;ll fill in the lower right hand side of my bingo card (although I already got Bingo today on the lower line&amp;hellip;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3 at #ESA 2012 - Decisions, Decisions</title>
      <link>/2012/08/08/day-3-at-esa-2012-decisions-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/08/08/day-3-at-esa-2012-decisions-decisions/</guid>
      <description>Man, this afternoon is going to be interesting. There are two sessions that I want to sit all the way through! I&amp;rsquo;ll be speaking in the Growing Pains in Ecology session, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be there all afternoon, but, the NutNet session looks pretty amazing as well.
OOS 33 - Growing Pains: Taking Ecology Into the 21st Century A106, Oregon Convention Center Organized by: C Strasser (carly.strasser@ucop.edu), J Tewksbury, S Hampton Moderator: C Strasser A discussion of the most important steps for ecology to take to address the complex problems set before our field by society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tentative #ESA2012 Tuesday</title>
      <link>/2012/08/07/tentative-esa2012-tuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/08/07/tentative-esa2012-tuesday/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday looks to be pretty exciting. The number of overlapping talks all of which I want to see has jumped up, and, heck, there are overlapping symposia that I could sit through. That said, I THINK this is going to be my schedule&amp;hellip;again, just posting it for myself, but feel free to browse (loading this page on ye olde smartphone and using it to navigate was wicked convenient today).
If there is one talk to see today, in my opinion, it&amp;rsquo;s the 10:50 COS 36-9 talk by Pamela Reynolds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My #ESA2012 Monday</title>
      <link>/2012/08/06/my-esa2012-monday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/08/06/my-esa2012-monday/</guid>
      <description>For the next few days, I&amp;rsquo;ll be trying to focus on two areas - 1) climate change &amp;amp; community responses and 2) biodiversity-ecosystem function - with probably a little network ecology thrown in for good measure. I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting my schedule here not because I want you to stalk me, but rather because it will be a convenient place for me to pull up on my phone to know where I&amp;rsquo;m going to go next!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>