<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ggplot2 on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</title>
    <link>/tags/ggplot2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ggplot2 on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ggplot2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelbased for Quick and Beautiful Model Visualization</title>
      <link>/2025/07/25/modelbased-for-quick-and-beautiful-model-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2025/07/25/modelbased-for-quick-and-beautiful-model-visualization/</guid>
      <description>A year ago, I found the modelbased package while looking for tools to visualize some mixed models. It was a minor revelation. Just like many of the packages from the [easystats]((https://easystats.github.io/) family.
I teach students to simulate the data they want for data viz (yay broom::augment() and modelr::data_grid()), and then plot that in combination with raw data (sometimes). This is great for really detailed nit-picky figures. But, particularly for students just learning, or for a quick-and-dirty data viz of a fit multivariate model, I always wished there was a simpler way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s All Go Down to the Barplot!</title>
      <link>/2009/09/03/lets-all-go-down-to-the-barplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/09/03/lets-all-go-down-to-the-barplot/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m back for another pean to ANOVA-loving experimental ecology. Barplots (or point-range plots - but which is better is a discussion for a different time) are the thing! And a friend of mine was recently asking me how to do a decent barplot with ggplot2 for data of moderate complexity (e.g., a 2-way ANOVA).
So I tried it.
And then I hit my head against a wall for a little while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Data Visualization</title>
      <link>/2009/07/16/simple-data-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/07/16/simple-data-visualization/</guid>
      <description>OK, so, I know I already raved about one Hadley Wickham project and how it has changed my life last week. But what can I say, the man is a genius. And if you are using R (and let&amp;rsquo;s face it, you should be) and you want simple sexy graphs made quick, the man has you covered once again.
I first learned about ggplot2 while scanning through some slides of the LA Area RUG meetings (that I missed - I still haven&amp;rsquo;t been to any!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>