<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science Music Videos on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</title>
    <link>/categories/science-music-videos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science Music Videos on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/science-music-videos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kelp &amp; German Death Metal</title>
      <link>/2014/08/12/kelp-german-metal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/08/12/kelp-german-metal/</guid>
      <description>I have no words for how amazing this is. New lab theme song?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beatles and Kelp</title>
      <link>/2014/08/07/the-beatles-and-kelp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/08/07/the-beatles-and-kelp/</guid>
      <description>For a blog post somewhere else, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to re-work the Beatle&amp;rsquo;s classic Kelp!, er, I mean, Help!. But my first draft got all urchin-y. I love it, though, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d post it here.
KELP! (from the perspective of a growing urchin)
Kelp! I need some algae. Kelp! not just any algae Kelp! You know I need some kelp!
When I was younger (So much younger than) so much younger than today (I never needed) I never needed any growing kelp in any way (Now) But now these days are gone (These days are gone), I don&amp;rsquo;t eat just diatoms (I know I&amp;rsquo;ve found) Now I find I&amp;rsquo;ve changed my mind and opened up my jaws</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ain&#39;t Nuthin&#39; but a Green Crab Thang</title>
      <link>/2014/01/03/aint-nuthin-but-a-green-crab-thang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/01/03/aint-nuthin-but-a-green-crab-thang/</guid>
      <description>Who knew Carcinus maenas could be so funky fresh? More awesomeness from Eric Axelman and folk from the Bertness lab.
Waring, NSFGC (or, you know, NSF_CM_)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fourth Annual Chemical Ecology Film Fest!!!</title>
      <link>/2013/12/12/fourth-annual-chemical-ecology-film-fest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/12/12/fourth-annual-chemical-ecology-film-fest/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s my most favorite time of year! Time for the science music video extravaganza known as the Annual Chemical Ecology Filmfest! It&amp;rsquo;s the fourth one! Congrats to Jeremy Long and all of his students for keeping this source of awesomeness going. Sit back, and take a look at a few here, or go over and watch the whole thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics Made Marvellous Through Dance</title>
      <link>/2013/10/03/statistics-made-marvellous/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/10/03/statistics-made-marvellous/</guid>
      <description>You all know I&amp;rsquo;m one for silly science videos. And silly statistics videos? Well, that&amp;rsquo;s like catnip to me.
But today my postdoc Alison introduced me to Dancing Statistics. And it is lovely.
In short, this troupe of dancers illustrates a wide variety of statistical concepts using naught but movement.
Now I just can&amp;rsquo;t wait until they get to p-values and Bayes&amp;rsquo; theorem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Les Miserables Larides</title>
      <link>/2013/06/18/les-miserables-larides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/06/18/les-miserables-larides/</guid>
      <description>One of the great things about field stations is the silliness they engender. I mean, there you are, in the middle of nowhere, with no one but other scientists thinking about the wonder of the natural world. Awe and wonder can only take you so far. And then, at some point, you cross over, and start to get a little silly.
It leads to things like dressing up as fouling panels, launching serious plans to make an &amp;lsquo;underwater office,&amp;rsquo; elaborate nail-polish-marking designs for crab carapaces, and no small number of pranks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m a Grazer, Baby!</title>
      <link>/2013/03/29/im-a-grazer-baby/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/03/29/im-a-grazer-baby/</guid>
      <description>You all know me. I&amp;rsquo;m a sucker for an awesome marine ecology music video. So it gives me great pleasure to present this product from the always amazing and ambitious ZEN (Zostera Experimental Network).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bertness Lab Anthem</title>
      <link>/2012/09/09/bertness-lab-anthem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/09/bertness-lab-anthem/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s always good to see some rockin&amp;rsquo; Science Music videos coming from my alma mater. The use of crabs here? Genius. Also great to see the Big Man Himself making a special guest appearance.
Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awww Yeah!  Chemical Ecology Music Video Extravaganza!</title>
      <link>/2011/12/08/awww-yeah-chemical-ecology-music-video-extravaganza/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/12/08/awww-yeah-chemical-ecology-music-video-extravaganza/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m so excited. It&amp;rsquo;s one of my favorite times of year. That&amp;rsquo;s right, it&amp;rsquo;s time for the Annual Chemical Ecology Music Video Festival! Oh, J. Long, what have your students cooked up this time?
Pure awesomeness, that&amp;rsquo;s what. This year&amp;rsquo;s crop features a number of epic ballads, rap superstars, and more. I think I&amp;rsquo;ll highlight my current two favorites, but you should definitely go check out the whole bunch or go back and revisit last year&amp;rsquo;s (particularly Under the Boat (featuring K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yo!  We&#39;re Climate Scientists! </title>
      <link>/2011/05/12/yo-were-climate-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/05/12/yo-were-climate-scientists/</guid>
      <description>I realize, I have been remiss as of late posting awesome science related videos. So&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Word to Your Tree Ring</title>
      <link>/2011/01/31/word-to-your-tree-ring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/01/31/word-to-your-tree-ring/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, this blog is about pure science. But lately, it appears I&amp;rsquo;ll be cataloging the increasing boom in Science related music videos. Because they&amp;rsquo;re awesome.
So be it.
The latest to be sent to my inbox (h/t Jenn Williams) is the Ecological Dynamics Rap made for Tom Wessel&amp;lsquo;s Ecological Dynamics of Landscapes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Your Reef On!</title>
      <link>/2011/01/18/get-your-reef-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/01/18/get-your-reef-on/</guid>
      <description>And here I thought that B-b-b-b-blue Whale would be stuck in my head all day. But now comes a second awesome marine science music video!
Two in one day! And it&amp;rsquo;s not even my birthday!
Thanks to J. Long of the recent Inducible Defense Rapinar for the pointer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I need some scat... prey base where you at?</title>
      <link>/2011/01/18/i-need-some-scat-prey-base-where-you-at/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/01/18/i-need-some-scat-prey-base-where-you-at/</guid>
      <description>I wish I could say something intelligible here, but, I love this so much and cannot stop rewatching it over and over&amp;hellip;the collision of marine bio nerdiness and pure awesome is a little overwhelming. Now if only there were tunicates involved&amp;hellip;
UBC.ZOOLOGY.GAGA.WHALE from Matt Siegle on Vimeo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>