<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>covid19R on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</title>
    <link>/categories/covid19r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in covid19R on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/covid19r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Roaring Back into Mobility in the US Post-Covid-Lockdown</title>
      <link>/2020/05/25/roaring-back-into-mobility-in-the-us-post-covid-lockdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/25/roaring-back-into-mobility-in-the-us-post-covid-lockdown/</guid>
      <description>As part of the Covid19R Project, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a new package, covid19mobility. It started as an effort to pull in the Apple Mobility Trends, and has since morphed as more mobility data comes out. Right now, I&amp;rsquo;m working through the Google Mobility Data, &amp;amp; I&amp;rsquo;m interested in the Descartes mobility data and any others you can suggest down below (link to source)! But the data itself - it&amp;rsquo;s FASCINATING!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Covid19R Project</title>
      <link>/2020/05/07/the-covid19r-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/07/the-covid19r-project/</guid>
      <description>We want our coronavirus data! We want it now! We want it TIDY!
tl;dr Go check out the Covid19R project and it&amp;rsquo;s documentation - a way for many people to bring their unique data harvesting efforts of Covid-19 data into a single tidy data format, and then be redistributed through a single low-dependency package, covid19R. It&amp;rsquo;s all one big work-in-progress, but check it out!
OK, the story! Back in February (remember February), while teaching data science, I was trying to think of ways to spice up the class with more relevant data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>