<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rantish on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</title>
    <link>/categories/rantish/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rantish on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/rantish/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Parenting as a Scientist in the Age of Climate Change</title>
      <link>/2016/01/21/parenting-as-a-scientist-in-the-age-of-climate-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/01/21/parenting-as-a-scientist-in-the-age-of-climate-change/</guid>
      <description>An old friend with a new child asked me if I know any climate change scientists or global change biologists who are parents and have written cogently about being parents in the era of climate change. Off of the top of my head, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t think of any (prove me wrong, internet), but, heck, I&amp;rsquo;m one myself. Here I am, staring down the barrel of hitting one year since HD&amp;rsquo;s arrival.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Positive Multifunctionality ≠ All Functions Are Positive</title>
      <link>/2014/09/25/positive-multifunctionality-all-functions-are-positive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/09/25/positive-multifunctionality-all-functions-are-positive/</guid>
      <description>Positive Multifunctionality ≠ All Functions Are Positive
I was dismayed this morning to read Bradford et al.&amp;lsquo;s recently accepted paper Discontinuity in the responses of ecosystem processes and multifunctionality to altered soil community composition in PNAS for several reasons.
The paper itself is really cool. They manipulated community complexity and nutrient conditions in the Ecotron, and then looked at five soil ecosystem functions. They then looked at whether complexity influenced multi functionality (as well as N), and found, indeed, it did!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Haus: The Future of Scholarly Publishing</title>
      <link>/2012/02/10/open-haus-the-future-of-scholarly-publishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/02/10/open-haus-the-future-of-scholarly-publishing/</guid>
      <description>Today at The National Center for Ecological Analysis and Synthesis we&amp;rsquo;re having an open discussion about the future of scholarly publishing. I may post some notes from it later, but, Stephanie Pau and I have compiled a list of thought questions and helpful links to help folk prep. And, as it was an interesting gathering of linkage, I thought it mide be useful more broadly. So, below is the text of my email and the useful links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Need to Understand Climate Change&#39;s Indirect Effects</title>
      <link>/2012/01/31/a-deficit-of-understanding-of-climate-changes-indirect-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/01/31/a-deficit-of-understanding-of-climate-changes-indirect-effects/</guid>
      <description>We know that warming, storms, drought, acidification, and the myriad of other effects of climate change will impact natural ecosystems. Most of our studies have concentrated on direct effects, though. For example, if you change temperature, you alter herbivore grazing rates. But what about indirect effects? For example, I&amp;rsquo;ve found that increased intense storm frequency may remove kelp which will have an indirect effect on the structure of kelp forest food webs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Vision for the Future of Scholarly Publishing</title>
      <link>/2012/01/31/a-vision-for-the-future-of-scholarly-publishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/01/31/a-vision-for-the-future-of-scholarly-publishing/</guid>
      <description>In many ways, the Research Works Act has been a blessing (see excellent link round up here). It has taken the moderately complacent but always grousing scientific community and whipped our feelings about the current state and cost of scientific publishing into a white hot fury. Ideas are bandied about, critiques given, and people begin to take action.
So what is the way forward? Certainly we are not getting away from journals in the near term.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should We Eat Fish?  The Online Discussion</title>
      <link>/2011/05/18/should-we-eat-fish-the-online-discussion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/05/18/should-we-eat-fish-the-online-discussion/</guid>
      <description>One of the main reasons science blogs excite me is the possibility of communication between scientists. It allows for a medium that scientists can use to hash out ideas and do so publicly. This has the added advantage that those who are not big names in a field or somesuch can listen in, as it were, or even step in and participate.
The discussion of science between scientists here, online, also has the added advantage of allowing the public to see inside of scientific debates and discussions in realtime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yo!  We&#39;re Climate Scientists! </title>
      <link>/2011/05/12/yo-were-climate-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/05/12/yo-were-climate-scientists/</guid>
      <description>I realize, I have been remiss as of late posting awesome science related videos. So&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privatizing the Reviewer Commons</title>
      <link>/2010/07/20/privatizing-the-reviewer-commons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/07/20/privatizing-the-reviewer-commons/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s face it. The current journal system is slowly breaking down - in Ecology if not in other disciplines as well. The number of submissions is going up exponentially. At the same time, journals are finding it harder and harder to find reviewers. Statistics such as editors contacting 10 reviewers to find 3 are not uncommon. People don&amp;rsquo;t respond, they take a long time to review, or just take a long time and THEN don&amp;rsquo;t respond leading to a need for still more reviewers to be found (this has held up 2 of my pubs for 3+ extra months).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Not Log-Transform Count Data, Bitches!</title>
      <link>/2010/06/17/do-not-log-transform-count-data-bitches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/06/17/do-not-log-transform-count-data-bitches/</guid>
      <description>OK, so, the title of this article is actually Do not log-transform count data, but, as @ascidacea mentioned, you just can&amp;rsquo;t resist adding the &amp;ldquo;bitches&amp;rdquo; to the end.
Onwards.
If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, when you learned experimental stats, you were taught to worship at the throne of the Normal Distribution. Always check your data and make sure it is normally distributed! Or, make sure that whatever lines you fit to it have normally distributed error around them!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>