<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>climate change on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</title>
    <link>/tags/climate-change/</link>
    <description>Recent content in climate change on I&#39;m a Chordata! Urochordata!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/climate-change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Discussion of Sea Level Rise on the US West Coast</title>
      <link>/2012/09/19/discussion-of-sea-level-rise-on-the-us-west-coast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/19/discussion-of-sea-level-rise-on-the-us-west-coast/</guid>
      <description>_X-posted from SeaMonster, this video is so clear, and so compelling that I thought it needed to put it up as well - 12&amp;rdquo; increase by 2050 in SoCal?! Wow. And 36&amp;rdquo; by 2100 in SoCal&amp;hellip;lots to think about. _</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story Behind the Paper: Climate Change and Kelp Forest Food Webs</title>
      <link>/2011/07/11/the-story-of-a-paper-climate-change-and-kelp-forest-food-webs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/07/11/the-story-of-a-paper-climate-change-and-kelp-forest-food-webs/</guid>
      <description>Yay! First paper of my postdoc is out in the August 2011 issue of Global Change Biology!
Woohoo!
So, what have I been doing for the past few years of my life?
In brief summary: Kelp. Food webs. Climate change. A potent combination.
And if you want the punchline without digging into the rest of this article, it is this: the diverse, complex food webs of southern California kelp forest will likely be greatly simplified if climate change leads to big storms every year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Dissertation in Under 7 Minutes</title>
      <link>/2010/04/01/my-dissertation-in-under-7-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/04/01/my-dissertation-in-under-7-minutes/</guid>
      <description>I recently attended the DISCCRS symposium for recent PhDs of a wide variety of disciplines whose work (past or present) deals with climate change. The week-long meeting was phenomenal, seeding me with thoughts, ideas, and basically making me feel quite good about the work I&amp;rsquo;m doing (if also very pessimistic about how society is dealing with Climate Change). Perhaps one of the most interesting exercises of the whole thing was something we had to do as a sort of getting-to-know-you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Future: Hot n&#39; Tasty?</title>
      <link>/2010/03/31/our-future-hot-n-tasty/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/03/31/our-future-hot-n-tasty/</guid>
      <description>Climate change. It&amp;rsquo;s going to wreak no small amount of havoc on mother nature (and if you&amp;rsquo;re reading this but think all of this climate change stuff is poppycock, please visit Skeptical Science and then come back). How good of a guide is our intuition for what will happen?
This is a great question when it comes to predator-prey relationships and the food chain. One may well think that, heck, from first principles we know that adding heat to a system speeds things up.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>